Tyler Maxwell

Contact

- phone
- email
- webpage
- GitHub
- LinkedIn

Personal Statement

Full stack web developer with a passion for making technology accessible to everyone. Experience several web development frameworks coupled with a background in law enforcement and education has cultivated an eclectic and pragmatic skill set. Fascination with web development has been a natural outgrowth of my commitment to lifelong learning and enduring love of technology. Strong skills in problem solving and leadership cultivated during my 20 plus years of diverse work experience would help organizations grow and thrive. Immune to pepper spray and teargas.

Technical Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Ruby on Rails
- React
- Redux

Technical Projects

- Personal Portfolio Website
 - Created using Jekyll
 - Hosted on Github Pages
 - Utilized custom Sass and Liquid and Markdown for front-end

Employment

- Nucamp, Bellevue, WA Instructor, February 2020 Present
 - Delivered instruction via Zoom to groups of 8 to 12 students in web development.
 - Managed and adapted instruction based on students' progress and proficiency with React and Redux.
 - Monitored student progress using formal and informal assessment tools both proscribed and self generated.
- Girls Who Code, Glendale, CA Facilitator, June 2019 August 2019
 - Delivered Computer Science lessons while maintaining an engaging and accessible classroom.
 - Managed and adapt instruction based on students' progress in and proficiency of hard and soft computer science skills.
 - Coordinated with a Teaching Assistant in classroom management, lesson delivery and logistical tasks.

- Los Angeles Unified School District, Los Angeles, CA Secondary Teacher, August 2007 -June 2012
 - Designed and taught year-long curriculum for Social Science for students in grades 7-12.
 - Collaborated with colleagues in other disciplines in order to incorporate STEM in the Social Science curriculum.
 - Created and maintained discipline system in the capacity of temporary dean of students.
- Los Angeles County Sheriff's Department, Los Angeles, CA Deputy Sheriff, September 1999 - August 2007
 - Provided law enforcement services in a variety of venues.
 - Prepared and maintained written and digital logs and reports for law enforcement records and court proceedings.
 - Functioned as an integral member of a criminal court staff by providing security and assisting in daily court proceedings.

Education

- College of the Canyons, Santa Clarita, CA Estimated Completion: 2021
 - Associate of Science: Computer Science (In Progress)
- National University, Los Angeles Los Angeles, CA 2006
 - Secondary Teaching Credential (Social Science)
- University of California, Los Angeles Los Angeles, CA 2001
 - Bachelor of Arts: Philosophy

Certifications

- Flatiron School 2018
 - Full Stack Web Development